export const GOVERNMENTA2001 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A state is sovereign only when",
A: "it protects its citizens well",
B: "the minorities are permitted in parliament",
C: "it owes no allegiance to any external power",
D: "there is absolute freedom in the state",
answer: "C. it owes no allegiance to any external power",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. One of the sources of a constitution is",
A: "referendum",
B: "conference",
C: "agreement",
D: "conventions.",
answer: "D. conventions",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. In which of the following system of government can the legislature dismiss a government through a vote of no confidence?",
A: "the presidential system of government",
B: "The parliamentary system of government",
C: "the federal system of government",
D: "the confederal system of government",
answer: "B. The parliamentary system of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The term constituency Implies",
A: "A local government area",
B: "An area designated for rallies",
C: "An area for political research",
D: "An electoral area",
answer: "D. An electoral area",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following countries practices the federal system of government?",
A: "Sierra Leone",
B: "The Gambia",
C: "Nigeria",
D: "Senegal.",
answer: "C. Nigeria",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Who was the Governor of the Gold Coast between 1942 and 1947?",
A: "Gordon Guggisberg",
B: "Arden Clarke",
C: "Alan Burns",
D: "Gerald Greasy",
answer: "C. Alan Burns",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Local authorities are established by",
A: "General elections",
B: "Parliamentary sub committees",
C: "Special presidential powers",
D: "Acts of parliament.",
answer: "D. Acts of parliament",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The National Congress of British West Africa ( NCBWA) failed to achieve its aims initially because",
A: "the chiefs and governors opposed the aims",
B: "African workers opposed the aims",
C: "The whites did not like the Black Africans",
D: "the leaders were very arrogant",
answer: "A. the chiefs and governors opposed the aims",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A unique feature of the 1946 Constitution of Ghana was",
A: "an elected unofficial majority in the legislative council",
B: "that Africans controlled the executive council",
C: "that the legislative council consisted solely of Europeans",
D: "that the governor’s wide powers were drastically reduced.",
answer: "A. an elected unofficial majority in the legislative council",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. In order to generate revenue, local authorities collect",
A: "income tax",
B: "excise duties",
C: "custom duties",
D: "property rates",
answer: "D. property rates",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A constitution is rigid if it",
A: "can be amended by a two – third majority",
B: "can be amended like an ordinary law",
C: "can be amended through a special procedure",
D: "cannot be amended.",
answer: "C. can be amended through a special procedure",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The lowest class of people in the hierarchy of the feudal system of government were the",
A: "nobles",
B: "Lords",
C: "Masses",
D: "serfs",
answer: "D. serfs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Decentralization as a system of government is desirable because it allows the",
A: "local authority to maintain a police force.",
B: "people to participate effectively in the administration of the locality",
C: "local authority to conduct its separate foreign policy.",
D: "central government to control the citizens directly.",
answer: "B. people to participate effectively in the administration of the locality",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The first military coup in Ghana was led by",
A: "Gen. E. K. Kotoka",
B: "Fit. Lt. J. J. Rawlings",
C: "Gen. I. K. Acheampong",
D: "Gen. F. W. K. Akuffo.",
answer: "A. Gen. E. K. Kotoka",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The principle of checks and balances is more noticeable in a",
A: "Parliamentary system of government.",
B: "presidential system of government",
C: "Fascist system of government,",
D: "monarchical system of government",
answer: "B. presidential system of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Aborigines Right Protection Society (ARPS) was formed in Ghana to",
A: "fight against colonial rule",
B: "protest against traditional rules",
C: "protest against indirect rule",
D: "protest against the lands bill.",
answer: "D. protest against the lands bill",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Nationalism in West Africa after the Second World War was aimed at",
A: "ending colonial rule",
B: "indigenizing the civil service",
C: "providing schools for Africans",
D: "ending colonial rule.",
answer: "A. ending colonial rule",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The organ of the United Nations Organization (UNO) which consists all the members is called tie",
A: "General Assembly",
B: "Economic and Social Council",
C: "Trusteeship Council",
D: "Security Council.",
answer: "A. General Assembly",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The West African Students Union (WASU) was formed in",
A: "Paris",
B: "London",
C: "Washington",
D: "New York",
answer: "B. London",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The delimitation of Ghana into constituencies is the responsibility of the",
A: "National Population Council",
B: "National Media Commission",
C: "Commission for Human Rights and Administrative Justice.",
D: "Electoral Commissioner",
answer: "D. Electoral Commissioner",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The official appointed to study the Watson Commission report after the 1948 Riots in the Gold Coast was",
A: "Henry Coussey",
B: "J. B. Danquah",
C: "Kwame Nkrumah",
D: "Gerald Greasy",
answer: "A. Henry Coussey",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Proto- nationalism in British West Africa was limited to",
A: "struggles among Africans themselves",
B: "demonstration by chiefs against the British",
C: "the elite protest against the British at the coast",
D: "Youth nationalist activities against the British",
answer: "C. the elite protest against the British at the coast",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Plebiscites are held to",
A: "vote on important national issues",
B: "give more powers to the president",
C: "demarcate constituencies",
D: "declare a state of emergency",
answer: "A. vote on important national issues",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The impartiality of the civil servants means that they",
A: "must not indulge in party politics",
B: "should serve the government of the day",
C: "must take blame or praise for their actions",
D: "can only serve the present government",
answer: "A. must not indulge in party politics",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. One of the major advantages of public opinion is that",
A: "It helps to change a government",
B: "It helps the government to know the wishes of the people",
C: "Workers are able to demonstrate without being arrested",
D: "every citizen expresses his or her opinion well",
answer: "B. It helps the government to know the wishes of the people",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Citizenship may be lost through",
A: "transferring it",
B: "delegating it",
C: "renouncing it",
D: "vote casting",
answer: "C. renouncing it",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The most significant achievement of the United Nations Organization since its formation is",
A: "prevention of a cold war between Western and Eastern powers blocs.",
B: "appointment of an African as the secretary – general",
C: "enlargement of its membership",
D: "prevention of another global war",
answer: "D. prevention of another global war",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The adoption of a bicameral legislature seeks to",
A: "offer representation to minorities",
B: "avoid wastage of the country’s resources",
C: "stop political opponents from entering parliament",
D: "satisfy supporters from the grassroots",
answer: "A. offer representation to minorities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Juvenile courts deal exclusively with misconduct by",
A: "minors",
B: "delinquent mothers",
C: "orphans",
D: "public servants",
answer: "A. minors",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Concurrent powers are exercised in a",
A: "fascist state",
B: "monarchical state",
C: "unitary state",
D: "federal state",
answer: "D. federal state",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Ghana attained a republican status in",
A: "1957",
B: "1960",
C: "1966",
D: "1972",
answer: "B. 1960",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Delegated Legislation Is Important because it",
A: "gives wide powers to the president",
B: "Is useful in times of emergency",
C: "helps to promote dictatorship",
D: "reduces government expenditure",
answer: "B. Is useful in times of emergency",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The West African state which was never under colonial rule is",
A: "The GambiaB.",
B: "Sierra Leone",
C: "Liberia",
D: "Burkina Faso",
answer: "C. Liberia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The principle of equality of all before the law in a state does not apply to",
A: "the armed forces",
B: "members of parliament",
C: "members of the cabinet",
D: "diplomats and envoys",
answer: "D. diplomats and envoys",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The second chamber in Britain is called the",
A: "House of Lords",
B: "Senate",
C: "House of Commons",
D: "House of Representatives",
answer: "A. House of Lords",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The most important prerequisite for the formation of a federal system of government is",
A: "effective administration",
B: "a supreme court to interpret the constitution",
C: "the desire for unity by component units",
D: "avoidance of dual citizenship",
answer: "C. the desire for unity by component units",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The general policies of public corporations are decided by the",
A: "workers union",
B: "sector minister",
C: "managing director",
D: "board of directors",
answer: "D. board of directors",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following is not a function of political parties",
A: "They ensure free and fair elections",
B: "They capture political power through elections",
C: "They educate the electorate on national issues",
D: "They provide links between the people and the government",
answer: "A. They ensure free and fair elections",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. For a written constitution to be effective, there should be",
A: "A parliament to discuss it",
B: "a supreme court to interpret it",
C: "an attorney general to defend it",
D: "a place to preserve it.",
answer: "B. a supreme court to interpret it",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. A bicephalous executive is a feature of the",
A: "presidential system of government",
B: "parliamentary system of government",
C: "monarchical system of government",
D: "federal system of government",
answer: "B. parliamentary system of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following is not a function of the Legislature?",
A: "Approving of national budgets",
B: "Serving as a forum for airing grievances",
C: "Impeaching the President",
D: "Administrating justice44. A major function of the judiciary is to",
answer: "D. Administrating justice",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A major function of the judiciary is to",
A: "interpret the laws",
B: "promulgate laws",
C: "confirm appointments",
D: "dismiss political appointees",
answer: "A. interpret the laws",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The term collective responsibility means that members of the cabinet",
A: "are jointly accountable for their actions",
B: "should belong to one party",
C: "are responsible to the chief justice.",
D: "are to attend all parliamentary sessions",
answer: "A. are jointly accountable for their actions",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. One of the functions of the traditional rulers under British Colonial Administration was to",
A: "make laws",
B: "make human sacrifices",
C: "judge criminal cases",
D: "collect taxes",
answer: "D. collect taxes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The concept of the rule of law implies the supremacy of the",
A: "executive",
B: "constitution",
C: "legislature",
D: "judiciary",
answer: "B. constitution",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Who was the head of government under the 1969 constitution of Ghana?",
A: "Edward Akuffo Addo",
B: "Kwame Nkrumah",
C: "Kof Abrefa Busia",
D: "Ako Adjei",
answer: "C. Kofi Abrefa Busia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. One of the weaknesses of the Guggisberg Constitution of Ghana was that",
A: "the legislative council was dominated by unofficial members",
B: "no member of the executive council could sit in the legislative council",
C: "only representatives from the North were allowed in the legislative council",
D: "Africans were totally excluded from the executive council",
answer: "D. Africans were totally excluded from the executive council",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The art of depriving persons of their right to vote is called",
A: "delineation",
B: "dismissal",
C: "disenfranchisement",
D: "disqualification",
answer: "C. disenfranchisement",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. Delegated Legislation includes laws made by",
A: "a Minister",
B: "Political Parties",
C: "Traditional Chiefs",
D: "Pressure Groups",
answer: "A. a Minister",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. Which of the following is not an objective of the Organization of African Unity (OAU)?",
A: "To settle disputes among citizens of member states",
B: "To eradicate all forms of colonialism from the continent of Africa",
C: "To promote unity and solidarity among member states",
D: "To offer financial assistance to member states",
answer: "A. To settle disputes among citizens of member states",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. The political system that allows individuals to own industrial and commercial enterprises is called",
A: "Capitalism",
B: "Totalitarianism",
C: "Socialism",
D: "Fascism",
answer: "A. Capitalism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. The French – Loi Cadre of 1956 aimed at",
A: "assimilating French West Africans",
B: "transferring political powers to French West Africans",
C: "giving independence to French West Africans",
D: "nominating Africans into the French Parliament",
answer: "B. transferring political powers to French West Africans",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. A representative system of government is one in which",
A: "civilians rule",
B: "those who rule are not elected",
C: "decisions are taken by consensus",
D: "those who govern are elected",
answer: "D. those who govern are elected",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. A court order directing a detainee to be brought before it is known as",
A: "habeas corpus",
B: "warrant of arrest",
C: "mandamus",
D: "writ of summons",
answer: "A. habeas corpus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. The first African secretary – general of the United Nations Organization was",
A: "Salim Ahmed Salim",
B: "Boutros Boutross Ghali",
C: "Kofi Annan",
D: "Diallo Telli",
answer: "D. Diallo Telli",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. A party’s manifesto is its",
A: "programme of action",
B: "emblem",
C: "electoral declaration",
D: "budget statement",
answer: "A. programme of action",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. The Public Service Commission in Ghana is responsible for the appointment of",
A: "judges of the superior courts",
B: "university teachers",
C: "workers of public corporation",
D: "civil servants",
answer: "D. civil servants",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. A government performs all the following functions except",
A: "keeping law and order",
B: "creating jobs avenues",
C: "ensuring economic development",
D: "confiscating citizens’ property without cause",
answer: "D. confiscating citizens’ property without cause",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]